Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
Petr Berngardovich Struve papers
1890-1987
79083
Hoover Institution Archives
58 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (24.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, essays, editorial files, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia relating to Russia in World War I, the Russian Revolution and Civil War, anti-Bolshevik movements, the Russian economy and industry, conditions in the Soviet Union after the Revolution, and Russian literary and political émigré affairs. Includes papers of the wife and sons of Petr Struve.
Struve, Petr Berngardovich, 1870-1944
Access
Boxes 1-45 closed. Microfilm use copies available.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979, with increments received in 1980, 1982, 1983, and 1985.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (59 reels).
Biographical Note
1870 Born, Perm, Russia
1894 Graduated from the University of St. Petersburg Published Critical Observations on the Problem of Russia's Economic Development
1897 Editor, Novoe Slovo
1899 Editor, Nachalo
1901 Arrested and banished from Petrograd Immigrated to Stuttgart, Germany Began publishing the weekly Osvobozhdenie (Stuttgart)
1905 Returned to Russia and joined the Constitutional-Democratic (Cadet) Party
1907 Elected to Second Duma
1907-1914 Editor, Russkaia Mysl' (Petrograd)
1914-1916 Member, Government Commission on Food Supply
1916 Awarded doctorate at Cambridge University
1917 Elected to the Russian Academy of Sciences Joined the Russian Provisional Government and resigned shortly afterward
1919 Editor, Velikaia Rossiia (Southern Russia)
1919-1921 Minister of Foreign Affairs, Volunteer (White) Army under General Vrangel'
1923-1924 Editor, Russkaia Mysl' (Prague)
1925-1927 Editor, Vozrozhdenie (Paris)
1927-1928 Editor, Rossiia (Paris)
1928-1934 Contributor, Rossiia i Slavianstvo (Paris)
1944 February 26 Died, Paris, France
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, essays, editorial files, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia relating to Russia in World War I, the Russian Revolution and Civil War, anti-Bolshevik movements, the Russian economy and industry, conditions in the Soviet Union after the Revolution, and Russian literary and political émigré affairs. Includes papers of the wife and sons of Petr Struve.
Incremental materials received subsequent to the creation of this register are listed at the end of the register.
Rossiiskoe TSentral'noe Ob'edinenie.; Vooruzhennye Sily na IUgie Rossii.; Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, Baron, 1878-1928.; Anti-communist movements.; Communism.; Refugees.; Rossiiskii Zarubezhnyi S'ezd (1926: Paris); Russia.; Russian literature.; Russians in foreign countries.; Soviet Union--Economic conditions.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History.; Soviet Union--Industries.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; Soviet Union.; Statesmen--Russia.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; World War, 1914-1918.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide for Boxes 1-45
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1912-1987 (Boxes 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material, including personal documents, calling cards, address books, reviews and other material related to biographies and biographical articles about Petr Struve, and clippings about Petr Struve from periodical press.
  - Genealogy of the Struve family, printed copy, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Personal papers
    - Documents, 1920-1943 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Calling cards and address books, 1931-1944 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Bills and receipts, 1925-1942 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Obituaries and letters of condolence on P. B. Struve's death, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Short biographies and chronologies of P.B. Struve's life, typescript, undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Reviews of biographies of P. B. Struve
    - Frank, Simon, Biografiia P. B. Struve
      - Koriakin, Iu. F., excerpt from untitled article, typescript, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
      - Mikhailov, S. E., "Pokhorony russkogo liberalizma. O knige S. L. Franka Biografiia P. B. Struve," typescript copy of article published in Voprosy filosofii, 1958 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Pipes, Richard, Struve, Liberal on the Left and Struve, Liberal on the Right
      - Struve, Gleb, comments and questions, typescript, undated (Box-folder 1: 9)
      - Miscellaneous reviews, printed copies, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Biographical articles re P. B. Struve
    - Borman, Arkadii, 1953-1971 (Box-folder 1: 11)
      Includes miscellaneous articles re P. B. Struve and responses from Gleb Struve, printed and typescript copies.
    - Kadomtsev, B. P., "Vospominaniia o Petre Berngardoviche Struve," typescript, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Lazarevskii, V., "O 'razmyshleniiakh' Struve," Russkaia Mysl', 1947 August 9 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Meiendorf, A. F., "P. B. Struve," holograph, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Pipes, Richard, "Peter B. Struve: The Source of His Liberal Russian Nationalism," tearsheet from Essays On Russian Liberalism, University of Missouri Press, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Putnam, George, "P. B. Struve's View of the Russian Revolution of 1905," The Slavonic Review, printed copy, 1967 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Ryss, Petr Ia., "Vospominaniia Petra Iakovlevicha Ryss o P. B. Struve," typescript, undated (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Struve, Arkadii, "Vzgliady P. B. Struve v gody vtoroi mirovoi voiny," typescript, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 18)
      Includes correspondence between Gleb Struve and N. A. Tsurikov.
    - Struve, Gleb
      - Miscellaneous holograph and typescript notes, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - "Dva 'liberal'nykh konservatora'. Iz perepiski P. B. Struve i V. A. Maklakova," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
      - "Eshche k iubileiu V. A. Maklakova i P. B. Struve," typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - "Iz Arkhiva P. B. Struve," printed copy, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - "K biografii P. B. Struve," letter to the editor of Russkaia Mysl', typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
      - "K 50-letiiu okonchaniia grazhdanskoi voiny na iuge Rossii," Mosty, printed copy, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 6)
      - "K stoletiiu so dnia rozhdeniia P. B. Struve," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
      - "Kn. D. P. Sviatopolk-Mirskii o P. B. Struve," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
      - "Piat'desiat let nazad: posledniaia stadiia grazhdanskoi voiny na iuge Rossii. Po neizdannym dokumentam iz arkhivov P. B. Struve i V. A. Maklakova," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - "P. B. Struve o smysle russkoi revoliutsii. Tri pis'ma k E. D. Kuskovoi," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
      - "P. B. Struve v gg. 1918-1919," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
      - "A Russian Liberal About the World Crisis of 1938-1939 and the Second World War," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Tsurikov, N. A., "Petr Berngardovich Struve. Vospominaniia," typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Vodov, S., "Liberal'nyi konservator," Russkaia Mysl', printed copy, 1964 February 27 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - Zander, L., "Svetloi pamiati Petra Berngardovicha Struve," Russkaia Mysl', printed copy, 1964 February 27 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Clippings re P. B. Struve from periodical press
    - Pre-revolutionary, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - Émigré, 1921-1983 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - Soviet, 1924-1979 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - P. B. Struve in Poland, newspaper clippings, 1921, 1959 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - General
    - Index of individuals associated with Petr Struve, typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 20)
    - List of lectures delivered at the Russian Scientific Institute in Belgrade from 1928-1938, typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 21)
    - Lecture announcements, reviews and reports on lectures, printed matter, 1923, 1952 (Box-folder 2: 22)
    - Indexes of writings and correspondence in P. B. Struve's archive, typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - Miscellaneous printed, typescript and handwritten material, 1925-1987 (Box-folder 2: 24)
      Includes short articles, book reviews, and notes.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1903-1970 (Boxes 3-15)
  Personal correspondence of Petr Struve, arranged alphabetically.
  - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - General
    - 1919-1943 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Typescript copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 1914-1947 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Photocopies of miscellaneous correspondence, 1927-1939 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Diplomatic dispatches and Civil War correspondence
    - General, 1920 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - 1920 September (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - 1920 October 2-28 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - 1920 October 11-28 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - 1920 October 20-25 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - 1920 October 26-31 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - 1920 November-December (Box-folder 3: 11-12)
  - Abaza, S., 1927 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Abrosimov, A., 1926 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Academic organizations, 1925-1938 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Adamantoff, P., 1927 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Aide aux savants, drafts of correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Agence de la presse illustrée, 1926 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Aide aux Étudiants Russes, 1926 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Aleinikov, N., 1926 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Aitova, M., undated (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Akimov, M., 1903 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Aleksinskii, I. P., 1927 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Alennikov, N. N., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Alexandre, Gaston, 1920 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Alger, Jules, 1920 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Amfiteatrov, Aleksandr, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    Includes photocopies.
  - Andreev, Andrei D., 1942 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Andronov, A., 1925 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Antonii, Metropolitan, 1926 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Apostol, P. N., 1923, 1925, 1942 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Archiv, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Argentova, Sofiia, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Arnol'di, K., 1927 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Artsybasheva, E., undated (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Arsen'ev, Iu. S., 1928 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Arsen'ev, Nikolai, 1920s (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Asmolov, V., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Association de Secours Mutuel et de Protection des Intérêts Suisses en Russie (Geneva), 1920 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Astrov, N. I., 1921 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Avenir (Paris), 1928 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Avraamii, Hierodeacon, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Baikalov, A., 1938 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Baikov, B., 1925 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Baiov, A. K., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Balakhovskaia-Peti, S. G., 1926, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Balkan, undated (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Bal'mont, Konstantin, 1932 (Box-folder 4: 27)
    Typescript copies. Includes letter to Sir Bernard Pares.
  - Banque Général Pour le Commerce Étranger, 1925 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Banque Générale Pour la France et Les Colonies (Paris), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Baratov, Gen. N. N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Bariatinskii, V., 1925 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Bark, P. L., 1920-1929 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Batanov, S., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Bebutova-Sollobgub, Countess, undated (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Beklemishev, P., 1920 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Beliaev, N., 1925 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Belitts, N. P., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Beng, Alfred L., 1931, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 38)
  - Bernatskaia-Savich, Olga, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 39)
  - Bernatskii, M. V., 1925-1928, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 4: 40)
  - Berthelot, M., 1920 (Box-folder 4: 41)
  - Bezsonov, G., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 42)
  - Bikerman, I. M., 1925-1929 (Box-folder 4: 43)
  - Bilimovich, Aleksandr, 1925-1943 (Box-folder 4: 44)
  - Blagov, Vladimir, 1926, 1928 (Box-folder 4: 45)
  - Bobrovskii, P. S., 1927 (Box-folder 4: 46)
  - Bogaevskii, A. P., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 4: 47)
  - Bogdanovich, Vladislav L., 1938 (Box-folder 4: 48)
  - Bogory, Natalie, undated (Box-folder 4: 49)
  - Boldyreva, Evgeniia A., 1920 (Box-folder 4: 50)
  - Bor'ba za Rossiiu, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 51)
  - Borman, A. A., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 4: 52)
  - Bortkevich, V., 1927 (Box-folder 4: 53)
  - Bostrem, Dmitry, undated (Box-folder 4: 54)
  - Bourkoff, Vladimir, 1927 (Box-folder 4: 55)
  - Bragin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 4: 56)
  - Brethauer, K., 1943 (Box-folder 4: 57)
  - Brianchaninov, A. N., 1925 (Box-folder 4: 58)
  - British Museum (London), 1925 (Box-folder 4: 59)
  - Brnenskii Filial Soiuza Russkikh Studentov v Chekho-Slovatskoi Respublike, 1926 (Box-folder 4: 60)
  - Brock, Olaf, 1934 (Box-folder 4: 61)
  - Brodnitz, George, 1925 (Box-folder 4: 62)
  - Brutskus, B., 1926-1928 (Box-folder 4: 63)
  - Bubnov, Nikolai M., 1924-1925 (Box-folder 4: 64)
  - Bulgakov, Sergei, 1926-1927, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 4: 65)
  - Bulgakova, E., undated (Box-folder 4: 66)
  - Bunin, Ivan A.
    - 1925-1943 (Box-folder 4: 67)
    - Typescript copies of above with introduction by Gleb Struve, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 68)
  - Bunitskaia, Elena, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Burnham, Lord, 1920 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Burtsev, Vladimir, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Butovich, Iuliia, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Callender, Harold, 1926(?) (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Cambridge University Library, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1943 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Chaikovskii, N. V., 1920 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Chebyshev, Nikolai N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Chelishchev, V. N., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Chernosvitov, Lev and B. V., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Chernosvitova, M., 1924-1944 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Chervinka, V. O., 1926 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Chubinskii, M. V., 1931 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Chukhnov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Chuprikov, M., 1932 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Clapham, Professor, 1938 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Comité National Russe, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Correard, J., undated (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Correspondance Universelle (Paris), 1920 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    Includes clipping of article "La tactique victorieuse de Wrangel," October 1920.
  - Danailov, Professor, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Daniel'-Bek, P., undated (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Davatts, Vladimir, 1925-1928, 1943 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Davydov, Leonid F., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Davydov, V., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Dekhtereva, Sofiia, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Demchenko, V., 1926 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Demosfenov, S. S., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Den, V. E., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Denikin, Lieutenant-General A., 1919-1927 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Denisov, N., 1920 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Dolgopolov, N., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Dolgorukii, Pavel and Petr, 1925-1944 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Dolin, N., 1937 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Dolinskii, N. V., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Dubasova, I. F., 1926-1928 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Dundukov, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Efremov, Ivan, 1927 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Efremov, Stepan F., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Elagin, A., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - El'iashevich, Fanna, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - El'iashevich, V. B., 1926, 1943 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Emelianoff, I. V., undated (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Engelhardt, B. W., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Engel'gardt, V., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Entente Internationale Contre la III Internationale, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Eriks-Polikarpoff, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Ermol'ev, Iosif N., 1920 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Evlogii, Metropolitan, 1926-1927, 1943 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Fedorov, Mikhail N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - Fedorova, Anna, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - Felichkin, Iurii, undated (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Felichkin, Mikhail, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Fenin, A. I., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Ficher, Nicolas, 1926 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Fisher, K., undated (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Filosofov, D., 1932 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Fiveiskii, P. M., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Florin, Ivan and Vera, 1930 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Florinskii, Mikhail, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 5: 61)
  - Florovskii, A. V., 1925-1932 (Box-folder 5: 62)
  - Florovskii, G. V., 1925 (Box-folder 5: 63)
  - Fondaminskii, I. I., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 64)
  - Formakov, A., 1926 (Box-folder 5: 65)
  - Francev, Vladimir A., 1926-1928, 1931-1941 (Box-folder 5: 66)
  - Franck, L., 1927 (Box-folder 5: 67)
  - Frank, Simon
    - 1926-1944 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Typescript excerpts of above, 1922-1943 (Box-folder 6: 2-4)
      Also includes index of correspondence between Petr Struve and Simon Frank.
  - Frank, Viktor, 1932 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Frankfurter Societats-Druckerei G.M.B.H., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Freeman, Alexander, 1927 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    Includes clippings of two articles, "Chetyre goda v SSSR," Russkaia Zhizn', October 1926 and "Seeks Freedom Finds Prison," unidentified newspaper, July 1926.
  - Frisch, R., 1926 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Gagilev, Konstantin I., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Ganfman, M. I., 1927-1928 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Gardner, Ekaterina, 1926 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Gaug, E., 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Gefding, V., 1925-1943 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Gerdov, Andrei, undated (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Gessen, I. V., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Giatsintov, N., 1938 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Ginzburg, M. B., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Girs, M. N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Glazberg, N. B., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - "Globtrotter,", 1925 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Goedlin de Tiefenau, E., 1928 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Goldstein, I. M., 1926 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Goldstein, M. L., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Goldstein, S., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Golovin, Gen. N. N., 1920-1926 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Gorelov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Gorovtsev, A., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 27)
    Includes tearsheet of article, "Pravovoe polozhenie ne-Sovetskoi Rossii," Obshchee Delo, 1921.
  - Gornyi, Sergei, 1924 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Gorskii, 1926 (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Gorchakov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Goux, Rene, undated (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Govory, B. I., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Gozdava-Guigitsky, Count Nicolas, undated (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - Grek, I., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - Grigorenko, A., undated (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - Grigorkov, Iurii A., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 36)
  - Grigor'ev, Dm., 1926 (Box-folder 6: 37)
  - Grimm, D. D., 1920, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - Grimm, Ivan D., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - Grimm, Maria V., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - Grinchenko, Leonid, 1925 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - Grinevich, Vadim, 1926 (Box-folder 6: 42)
  - Grinevich, Vera, 1925 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - Grosse, Lev, 1925 (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - Grube, E., 1921 (Box-folder 6: 45)
  - Grunichev, Gavriil, 1925 (Box-folder 6: 46)
  - Gruner, M., 1920 (Box-folder 6: 47)
  - Guchkov, A. I., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 6: 48)
  - Guchkov, N. I., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 49)
  - Guins, George, 1938 (Box-folder 6: 50)
  - Gukasov, A. O., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 6: 51)
  - Gukasov, P. O., 1928 (Box-folder 6: 52)
  - Gurevich, Grigorii, 1926 (Box-folder 6: 53)
  - Gurko, V. I., 1923-1925 (Box-folder 6: 54)
  - Gurskaia, A. A., 1927(?) (Box-folder 6: 55)
  - Haumont, E., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 6: 56)
  - Herder and Company, 1927 (Box-folder 6: 57)
  - Hildebrand, Nina, undated (Box-folder 6: 58)
  - Hoare, Sir Samuel, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 6: 59)
    Also includes letters of Gleb Struve.
  - Holsti, M., 1920 (Box-folder 6: 60)
  - Iablonskii, A. A., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 61)
  - Iablonskii, S., 1925 (Box-folder 6: 62)
  - Iakovenia, I., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 63)
  - Ianushevskii, G. E., 1926 (Box-folder 6: 64)
  - Iasenskaia-Gantz, Z., undated (Box-folder 6: 65)
  - Iatsenko, E., undated (Box-folder 6: 66)
  - Iashvil', A., undated (Box-folder 6: 67)
  - Ijboldine, Boris, 1928, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Il'iashevich, M., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Il'in, Ivan A.
    - 1925-1927 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Typescripts and photocopies, 1925-1940 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Il'in, Sergei N., 1920 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Il'in, V., 1922-1927 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Illiustrirovannaia Rossiia (Paris), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Institute of International Education (New York), 1925 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Ionov, E. T., 1928 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Iordansky, M. G., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Isaakii, Arkhimandrite, 1937 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Iuzefovich, Iakov D., 1920 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Ivanov, Evgenii, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Ivanov, Ivan, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Ivanov, P., 1926(?) (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Ivanov, Vsevolod, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Ivanova, Olga, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Ivantsov, D., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Izgoev, A. S., 1925-1931 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Iznar, N. N., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1932 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Jovanovich, Slobodan, 1941 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Kadlets, K., undated (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Kadomtsev, B. P., 1927-1928, 1932 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Kalin, Aleksandr, 1925 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Kaminka, August, 1925, 1932 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Kandakova, Vera, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Kandakova, Z., undated (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Karabchevskii, N., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - Karavodina, L., 1943 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Karrik, Valerii, 1925 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Karsavin, L., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 32)
  - Kartashev, Anton V., 1926-1928, 1942 (Box-folder 7: 33)
  - Kashirskii, L., undated (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Kashkarov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Kassian, Arkhimandrite, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 36)
  - Katkov family, 1927, 1937 (Box-folder 7: 37)
  - Kaz'mina, Inna, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 38)
  - Kefeli, Ia., 1943 (Box-folder 7: 39)
  - Keller, V., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 40)
  - Kishenskaia, V., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 7: 41)
  - Khit'kov, Aleksandr, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 42)
  - Khlytchieva, Tatiana I., 1932, 1937-1938, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 43)
  - Khmel'nikova, Anna, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 44)
  - Kholmsen, Lieutenant-General I., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 45)
  - Khomenko, Aleksandr, 1920 (Box-folder 7: 46)
  - Khreptovich-Butenev, K. A., 1927, 1931 (Box-folder 7: 47)
  - Khripunov, A. S., 1925-1932 (Box-folder 7: 48)
  - Khvostov, Aleksei, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 49)
  - Kirchenrat in Hamburg, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 50)
  - Kirienko, Major-General Ivan, 1925 (Box-folder 7: 51)
  - Kishenskii, D., 1926-1928 (Box-folder 7: 52)
  - Kizevetter, A. A., 1925-1927, 1931 (Box-folder 7: 53)
  - Klavdiev, Vasilii, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 54)
  - Kletkova, E., undated (Box-folder 7: 55)
  - Klopotovskii, V., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 56)
  - Kobets, B., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 57)
  - Kocharovskii, K., 1932 (Box-folder 7: 58)
  - Kokoshkina, Vera, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 59)
  - Kokovtsev, Count V. N., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 60)
  - Kolenko, A., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 61)
  - Kolzakov, Boris, 1926 (Box-folder 7: 62)
  - Kon, Stanislas, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 7: 63)
  - Konius, Tatiana, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 64)
  - Konovalov, Aleksandr, 1920 (Box-folder 7: 65)
  - Kopylov, A., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 66)
  - Korchemyni, V., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 67)
  - Korenchevskii, V., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 68)
  - Koshits, Nina, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 69)